A Finding Aid to the Roger Crossgrove Papers, 1888-2012, bulk 1950-2006, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Roger Crossgrove papers
1888-2012
bulk 1950-2006
Archives of American Art
Crossgrove, Roger, 1921-
AAA.crosroge
Archival Resource Key
21.1 Linear feet
The papers of Connecticut painter, educator, photographer, and watercolorist Roger Crossgrove measure 21.1 linear feet and date from 1888 to 2012 with the bulk of the collection dating from 1950 to 2006. The collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, writings and notes, professional files, teaching files, subject files, exhibition files, printed materials, personal business records, artwork, sketchbooks, and photographic materials.
Biographical / Historical
Roger Crossgrove (1921-2016 ) is a painter, photographer, and educator working at the University of Connecticut in Storrs, Connecticut and who is best known for his monotype watercolors.
Roger Crossgrove was born in Farnam, Nebraska. He attended the University of Nebraska where he received his Bachelor of Fine Arts degree in 1949. In 1950, he spent a year painting in Mexico and later returned to live for another year in 1965. In 1951, he received a Master of Fine Arts from the University of Illinois. He also participated in the Yaddo Fellowship in Saratoga Springs, New York for several years beginning in 1957.
From 1953 to 1967, Crossgrove taught at the Pratt Institute's Art School and the Department of Graphic Art and Illustration in Brooklyn, New York, teaching under Albert Christ-Janer for some of that period. He moved to Storrs, Connecticut to teach at the University of Connecticut's School of Fine Arts where he served as head of the Art Department for 20 years. After retiring in 2008, he was awarded Professor Emeritus status and, in 2008, a Lifetime Achievement Award from the university.
Although Crossgrove produced artwork in various mediums over the course of his career, his monotypes are some of his most prolific works. Numerous exhibitions throughout the United States and Mexico have featured Crossgrove's monotypes and other works of art.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Connecticut painter, educator, photographer, and watercolorist Roger Crossgrove measure 21.1 linear feet and date from 1888 to 2012 with the bulk of the collection dating from 1950 to 2006. The collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, writings and notes, professional files, teaching files, subject files, exhibition files, printed materials, personal business records, artwork, sketchbooks, and photographic materials.
Biographical materials consist of appointment notebooks and planners, awards, calendars, a marriage announcement, and graduate school coursework. Correspondence is with family, friends, colleagues, museums, and galleries. Correspondents include American Artists Group, Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, the Philadelphia Museum of Art, and artists Eric Carle, John Schoenherr, Joseph A. Smith, Antonia Torres, and Alfredo Zalce, among others.
Writings and notes include essays, a thesis by Crossgrove, a play manuscript, notebooks, and notes. There are also writings by Justino Fernandez about contemporary Mexican prints. Professional files contain correspondence, printed materials, and notes related to Crossgrove's involvement with various arts organizations, the Yaddo Fellowship, and other professional activities. Teaching files contain documents compiled during Crossgrove's tenure at the Pratt Institute and the University of Connecticut.
Subject files created by Crossgrove about topics of interest, Mexican art, and artists Milton Avery, Romare Bearden, and others contain clippings, exhibition catalogs, and museum publications. Exhibition files are both general and specific. There are files for Roger Crossgrove Selected Works: Photographs 1978-1993, Three Decades (1961-1990): Works on Paper and Photographs, and numerous additional exhibitions of Crossgrove's work.
Personal business records document loans and sales of Crossgrove's artwork, purchases of artwork, personal ledgers, and expense lists. Printed materials include clippings, invitations, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, flyers, gallery and museum publications, periodicals, and posters.
Artwork consists of drawings, illustrations, and monotypes by Crossgrove, as well as photographs by Steve Balkin, and artwork by Louis Owens, Vincent Perez, and Warner Pfeiffer. Eighteen sketchbooks contain drawings and notes by Crossgrove. Photographs and negatives are of Crossgrove, artwork, family and friends, and travel.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Roger Crossgrove papers were donated by Roger Crossgrove in 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 12 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1888-2002 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 1-2, 23, OV 24)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1921-2000s (1.5 linear feet; Boxes 2-3)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1951-2000 (0.5 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 4: Professional Files, 1951-2009 (2.5 linear feet; Boxes 3-6)
Series 5: Teaching Files, 1953-2009 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 6-7, 23)
Series 6: Subject Files, 1950s-1999 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 7-8, OV 24)
Series 7: Exhibition Files, 1950-2005 (3.0 linear feet; Boxes 8-11)
Series 8: Personal Business Records, 1963-2009 (0.2 linear feet; Box 11, OV 24)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1906-2012 (8.5 linear feet; Boxes 11-20, 23, OV 24)
Series 10: Artwork, 1933-2000 (0.5 linear feet; Boxes 20, 23)
Series 11: Sketchbooks, 1950s-1980s (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 20, 22-23)
Series 12: Photographic Material, 1920s-2006 (0.4 linear feet; Boxes 21)
Photographs; Art, Mexican; Art -- Study and teaching; Art teachers -- Connecticut; Painters -- Connecticut; Illustrations; Drawings; Watercolorists -- Connecticut; Photographers -- Connecticut; Sketchbooks; Prints; Brooks Memorial Art Gallery; Perez, Vincent; Fernández, Justino, 1904-1972; Carle, Eric; Balkin, Steve; Owens, Louis; Zalce, Alfredo, 1908-2003; Pfeiffer, Werner, 1937-; Schoenherr, John; Smith, Joseph A. (Joseph Anthony), 1936-; Torres, Antonia; Yaddo (Artist's colony); Philadelphia Museum of Art; University of Connecticut -- Faculty; American Artists Group; Pratt Institute -- Faculty; Avery, Milton, 1885-1965; Bearden, Romare, 1911-1988
- Biographical Material, 1888-2002; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 1, 23, OV 24
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials include eighteen annotated calendars, five appointment notebooks, and nine daily planners. Also included are awards and medals from various arts organizations and competitions. Crossgrove's marriage announcement, membership cards, receipts and payments, and files related to his M.F.A. coursework at the University of Illinois are also found in this series.
  - Appointment Notebooks, 1987-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appointment Notebooks, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointment Notebooks, 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Notebook and Travel Information, Mexico, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Awards, General, 1951-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards, Photography Contest Medals from Manchester Community College, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Calendars, 1962-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7-16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23
  - Daily Planners, 1951-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17-22)
  - Genealogy, 1888-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Handkerchiefs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Marriage Announcement, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Medical Information, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Membership Cards, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Resumes, 1949-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Student Records, 1946-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - University of Illinois, Master of Fine Arts Coursework and Architecture Timeline, 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Oversized Calendar from Box 1, Folders 7-16, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
  - Oversized University of Illinois, MFA, Architecture Timeline from Box 1, Folder 30, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
- Correspondence, 1921-2000s; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Correspondence is with friends, family, organizations, museums and galleries, colleagues, and artists. Correspondence is with American Artists Group, Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, and Philadelphia Museum of Art, and for artists such as Eric Carle, Joseph A. Smith, John Schoenherr, Antonia Torres, and Alfredo Zalce, among others.
  - People and Organizations, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - American Artists Group, 1968-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1947-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Brown, John, United States Cultural Attaché, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Carle, Eric, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Editorial Reverté Mexicana, S.A., 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - International Institute of Arts and Letters, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Schoenherr, John, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Joseph A., circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Torres, Ma. Antonia, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Zalce, Alfredo, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Topics, Archival Resource Key
    - Exhibitions, 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Family, 1974-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Greeting Cards, Christmas, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Greeting Cards, Get Well, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Incoming, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letterhead, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mexico, 1962-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Student Complaints, University of Nebraska, circa 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - General, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - General, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
  - General, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - General, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - General, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - General, 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- Writings and Notes, 1951-2000; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3
  Writings by Crossgrove include a report on Tarascan, Mexico, a master of fine art thesis report, and a student paper titled "Some Observations on the Graphic Arts of Modern Mexico". There are notes and notebooks, a music writing book, and a manuscript draft written by Dr. Justino Fernández for a Mexican prints exhibition catalog. Some of the notebooks are also illustrated.
  - Report on Tarascan, Mexico by Crossgrove, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Some Observations on the Graphic Arts of Modern Mexico" by Crossgrove, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - University of Illinois, Master of Fine Art Thesis Report by Crossgrove, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Drafts by Dr. Justino Fernández for Contemporary Mexican Prints Exhibition Catalog, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Modern Art and Mount Olympus, Play Manuscripts, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Music Writing Book, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Notebooks, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Notebooks, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Notes, General, circa 1966-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notes, Columbia University Course with Michael Patrick Hearn, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Notes, "Luis Frangella-Heavy Air-Raw", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Notes, Resources for Art Books, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Notes, Spiral Staircase, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Notes, Suppliers for Frames and Plexi, 1969-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Professional Files, 1951-2009; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 3-6
  Professional files document Crossgrove's involvement in several arts organizations including the American Artists Group, American Watercolor Society, Artworks Gallery, Atrium Gallery, Brooklyn Society of Artists, Children's Book Council, Greater Mansfield Council for the Arts, Mystic Art Association, and the Windham Regional Arts Council. There are also files relating to the Yaddo Fellowship. Files typically contain administrative documents, correspondence, expense records, membership records, and printed materials.
  - American Artists Group, 1964-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1955-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - American Watercolor Society, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
  - Artworks Gallery, General, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Artworks Gallery, General, 1980-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2-8)
  - Artworks Gallery, General, 1986-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Artworks Gallery, General, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Artworks Conference, Profiles of Members, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Artworks Gallery, 30th Anniversary Honoring Crossgrove, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Artworks Gallery, Exhibitions, 1984-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Artworks Gallery, Exhibitions, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Artworks Gallery, Plateaus (1988), circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Artworks Gallery, Romare Bearden Exhibition, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Atrium Gallery, 1977-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Barnes Foundation, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bibliography List for Illustrators Lauren Mills and Dennis Nolan, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn Society of Artists (American Society of Contemporary Artists), 1957-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Children's Book Council, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Children's Book Illustration, circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - College Art Association, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts, 1972-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Connecticut Book Fair, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Connecticut Ceramics Co-op, 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Emily Lowe Award, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Graphic Arts Programs, 1958-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Greater Mansfield Council for the Arts, General, 1989-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Greater Mansfield Council for the Arts, Nominating Committee, 1990, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Leddick, David, Book Project, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - List of Artist Models for Photographs, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Mystic Art Association, Meeting Minutes, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rosenwald Collection of the National Gallery of Art, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Springfield Art League, 1972-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Subscription Information to Art Periodicals, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Teaching Applications, 1951-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Tiffany Foundation, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Travel Itineraries, 1970-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Vermont College Master of Fine Art Program, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Visual Images Gallery, 1978-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - West Hartford Art League, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Windham Regional Arts Council, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Yaddo Fellowship, 1957-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Yaddo Fellowship, 1992-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Teaching Files, 1953-2009; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 6-7, 23
  Teaching files consist of correspondence, campus information, faculty memos and procedures, and student coursework compiled during Crossgrove's professorship at the Pratt Institute, where he taught under Albert Christ-Janer, and the University of Connecticut. Also included are letters regarding Crossgrove's independent study in Mexico and his sabbatical from the University of Connecticut, a collage in honor of Crossgrove's retirement, research questionnaire materials, and Crossgrove's statements on his career while at the University of Connecticut.
  - Pratt Institute, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - General, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - General, 1957-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - General, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 102nd Commencement Script, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Burser's Office, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Class Notes and Photographs on Still Life Painting, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Eichenberg, Fritz, Chairman of Department of Graphic Arts, 1953-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Evening Art School, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Independent Study in Mexico, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Material Regarding Faculty and Petition, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Meeting Agendas, 1961-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Print Exhibition and Sale, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - University of Connecticut, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - General, 1968-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - Bookmark, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Commencement Program, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cover Pages of "Annual Report of University of Connecticut Faculty Alumni Center Inc.", 1971-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Cynthia Reeves Snow Award, 1977-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Eichenberg, Fritz, Exhibition and Lecture, 1979-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Emeritus Faculty Handbook, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Faculty-Alumni Center, 1968-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Flyers for Crossgrove's Watercolor Monotypes, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Grading Instructions, 1972-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Latin American Studies, 1973-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Libraries, 1978-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Maps of University and Storrs, Connecticut, 1971-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Merit Procedures, 1980-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Picture Book Illustration Course Student Autobiographies and Notes, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Picture Book Illustration Course Student Index Cards, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Recreation Schedules, 1974-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Research Foundation Grant 1982, 1981-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Resumes and Statements on Career, 1981-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Retirement Collage, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Sabbatical, 1972-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - School of Fine Arts, Dean's Advisory, 1982-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - School of Fine Arts, Development, 1980-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - University of Connecticut, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - Semester on the 1930s, circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Visiting Artist Program, Special Events, 1977-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - General, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - Course Outlines, Product Structure, 1953-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letter Recommendation Form, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Materials for Research Questionnaire, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Paperbound Books in Print, 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Washington, D.C.-National Gallery, Library of Congress, etc., 1966-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Pratt Institute, Petition from Box 6, Folder 13, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
- Subject Files, 1950s-1999; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 7-8, OV 24
  Subject files were compiled by Crossgrove on artists and art related topics of interest, such as Mexico. Mexican art, city redevelopment projects, and artists Milton Avery, Romare Bearden, Edgar Degas, Tomie de Paola, and Rufino Tamayo. Files typically contain printed materials.
  - Anatomy for Art Students, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Avery, Milton, 1972-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Bearden, Romare, 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Belkin, Arnold, 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Citron, Minna, 1956-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cortez, Jayne, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Degas, Edgar, 1960-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - De Paola, Tomie, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Frank, Mary, 1973-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Kaelin, Phil, circa 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Lindner, Richard, 1954-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Mexico, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Mexico, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Prindle, Janice, Material Regarding "Belles Lettres", 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Redevelopment Projects, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Oversized material housed in OV 24
  - Samaras, Lucas, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tamayo, Rufino, 1969-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)